Hello again in this new section about the digital aspects of the NFC communication.
So through the section I will present the different digital aspects of the NFC communication between
the PAC and the PCD.
I mean between a card and a reader.
In fact, in this first presentation of this section, I will talk about the progress of a type A communication.
As you have seen before, the ISO 14,443 presents two different types of communication type A and type
B.
When we talk about digital aspects, we talk about comments from the reader and answers from the cards.
So we talk about bytes, we talk about timings, we talk about returns of each and form of each command
and each answer.
We talk about exchange of information.
We talk about uh, uh, responses and comments that give us information about the speed, the timings,
the UID, etc., etc..
So first of all, here is an example of the sequence of a type A communication.
So first of all the first state is the power of state.
So when we don't have a card and we don't in the field and we don't have the field activated, so then
when we activate the field and we put the card into the field, we pass to the idle state.
So this is the second state of the communication of the sequence.
Then once done we will we will send the first command.
It's a request a or a wake up a.
We will go through these type these commands and this answer in the next presentation.
So when we are in the idle state, the reader will send a first command, which is a request A or A
wake up, a req, a WPA.
Then the answer to this command will be the atca the answer from the card.
Once done, the card will go to the ready state inside the ready state.
We will do the phenomenon called the phenomenon of anti-collision.
It's the phenomenon that we will will be applied or will be very useful when we have many cards into
the field.
Once done, the reader will send the select command in order to select the card.
The answer to this select command will be the sack.
Select acknowledgment.
Once done, the card will move to the active state and then the reader will send the Arete's command
request to answer to select and the answer for that from the card will be ATS answer to select.
And in the end we will have the protocol state, which is the protocol.
We will perform the PS command and the PS response.
And this command response will be the protocol exchange, where we will select the speed that we will
use for the rest of the communication.
So as we have seen before, there are several for normal types of bitrates.
For values of the speed 106, 212 for 24 and 848.
The choice of this speed will be done inside this protocol state.
So here I'm presenting from through this table the communication sequence.
So as I said the first stage is the power of here.
The card is not powered by a reader operating field.
Second we have the idle state where the card is powered and waiting for commands.
Request a or wake up a.
Third, we have the ready state where the Anti-collision method should be applied.
Fourth, we have the active state where the card should be ready to accept the protocol activation command
or ATS request to answer to select.
And finally, the protocol state, which is the protocol negotiation and the data block transmission
may be performed.
So here is an example of a communication sequence.
So as I said first of all we have the power of state.
Then we will activate the field.
The card will be in the idle state.
Once done we will send a request A or a wake up A, so the card will move to the ready state.
Inside the ready state, we will perform the Anti-collision.
Once done, the reader will send the select command.
So the card will go to the active state and then the.
The reader will send the ATS request to answer to select, and after that, the card will go into the
protocol state where we will perform the the speed negotiation and the block transmissions.